<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Elias&#39; blog</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Elias&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Setup</title>
      <link>/posts/setup/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/setup/setup/</guid>
      <description>This is my current workspace. I designed it to be both calming and beautiful while also being modern and minimalistic: That&amp;rsquo;s my stuff:
Laptop: HP Pavilion Gaming Laptop (modded specs, secret 🙃) OS: Windows and Linux 😎 Monitor: Samsung Odyssey G4 (1080p @240Hz) Keyboard: Keychron K4 Mouse: Logitech G Pro Wireless Fan: Noname but cool and it has a light :) You can also notice I decorated the wall a little.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This is my current workspace. I designed it to be both calming and beautiful while also being modern and minimalistic:
&lt;img alt=&#34;my workspace&#34; src=&#34;workspace.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s my &lt;strong&gt;stuff&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laptop: HP Pavilion Gaming Laptop (modded specs, secret 🙃)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OS: Windows and Linux 😎&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor: Samsung Odyssey G4 (1080p @240Hz)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard: Keychron K4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mouse: Logitech G Pro Wireless&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fan: Noname but cool and it has a light :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also notice I &lt;strong&gt;decorated the wall&lt;/strong&gt; a little. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it:
The &lt;strong&gt;right picture&lt;/strong&gt; was drawn by my grandfather, who was an artist. The &lt;strong&gt;picture to the very left&lt;/strong&gt;, I drew myself, as you might assume by the excellence of it.
I got the picture of the &lt;strong&gt;Holy Family in Egypt&lt;/strong&gt; from church. The &lt;strong&gt;silver cross&lt;/strong&gt; was a gift from my cousin (also got it from church).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I have got the big &lt;strong&gt;Calendar&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evn.at/&#34;&gt;EVN&lt;/a&gt;, which I personally requested and was granted exclusive access on :D It&amp;rsquo;s really helpful as it grants me a perfect overview on all my exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you might have recognized I got a little forearm training device which I use while coding or if I&amp;rsquo;m just bored&amp;hellip; #neverStopTraining 💪&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post surely can help you if you are currently seeking inspiration for your own setup. If it did help you, I would be happy if you let me know and maybe show me a pic of your setup 📸✌️&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a blog project that reads Markdown files and converts them to HTML using Hugo 🔥
Benefits Hosting cost Using this approach I am able to minimize hosting costs as far as possible, since only HTML files are served and I don&amp;rsquo;t require a database.
Theming Hugo enables theming and many skilled designers have published their cool themes which can easily be imported and used. So, no more centering divs myself :)</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a blog project that reads Markdown files and converts them to HTML using
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo 🔥&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;benefits&#34;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hosting-cost&#34;&gt;Hosting cost&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this approach I am able to minimize hosting costs as far as possible, since
only HTML files are served and I don&amp;rsquo;t require a database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;theming&#34;&gt;Theming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo enables theming and many skilled designers have published their cool themes
which can easily be imported and used. So, no more centering divs myself :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-i-help&#34;&gt;Can I help?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you can. If you are familiar with Hugo and spot a flaw in my config files or
just have a better approach, pls contact me via the contact section at my portfolio
site &lt;a href=&#34;https://eliaskelta.com&#34;&gt;eliaskelta.com&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beetle X31 SSD</title>
      <link>/posts/ssd/ssd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ssd/ssd/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Yesterday my Beetle X31 SSD was delivered. I ordered it because it was heavily discounted on the black friday sale (70€). I ordered the 1TB Version to extend my external storage possibility as far as possible.
Product Package Content Inside the package was:
The SSD itself A protective case for the SSD Two extra thicc USB 3.0 cables: USB type C - USB type C cable USB type C - USB type A cable A little manual #skipthetutorial 🙃 Benchmarks As soon as it arrived, I ran a few benchmark tests on the external SSD.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday my Beetle X31 SSD was delivered. I ordered it because it was heavily discounted on the black friday sale (&lt;strong&gt;70€&lt;/strong&gt;). I ordered the &lt;strong&gt;1TB&lt;/strong&gt; Version to extend my external storage possibility as far as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;product&#34;&gt;Product&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Beetle X31 SSD&#34; src=&#34;beetle.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;package-content&#34;&gt;Package Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the package was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The SSD itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A protective case for the SSD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two extra &lt;em&gt;thicc&lt;/em&gt; USB 3.0 cables:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB type C - USB type C cable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB type C - USB type A cable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A little manual #skipthetutorial 🙃&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;benchmarks&#34;&gt;Benchmarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as it arrived, I ran a few benchmark tests on the external SSD. Here are the results:
&lt;img alt=&#34;benchmark results&#34; src=&#34;benchmark.png&#34;&gt;
&amp;hellip; And yes, I used Windows 4 this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the results are really great and the Beetle X31 SSD is performing as advertised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Beetle X31 SSD is a high performing external SSD at a low price range. I totally recommend buying it, especially when in discount.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first blog entry</title>
      <link>/posts/first-post/first-blog-entry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/first-post/first-blog-entry/</guid>
      <description>This is the first entry in my blog. I am testing a few things here:
Get it to work Get images to work Get Code to be displayed properly Get publishing to work Images Here is an image of my beautiful desktop environment: Code System.out.println(&amp;#34;Hello, world!&amp;#34;); </description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This is the first entry in my blog. I am testing a few things here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get it to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get images to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get Code to be displayed properly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get publishing to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;images&#34;&gt;Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an image of my beautiful desktop environment:
&lt;img alt=&#34;gnome-desktop&#34; src=&#34;my-gnome-desktop.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34; data-lang=&#34;java&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;System.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;println&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Hello, world!&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The idea behind this</title>
      <link>/posts/idea/idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/idea/idea/</guid>
      <description>I always wanted to develop a post where I could write inspiring stuff about my life and programming carrier. But the problem always was, that hosting a big ass web app with a database and everything would result in high hosting cost. To avoid this, I came up with this solution:
I write my posts in Markdown I translate the Markdown to HTML using Hugo I run a custom bash script to polish everything off I automatically publish the site to Vercel through a GitHub push </description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to develop a post where I could write inspiring stuff about my life and programming carrier. But the problem always was, that hosting a big ass web app with a database and everything would result in high hosting cost.
To avoid this, I came up with this solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I write my posts in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I translate the Markdown to HTML using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I run a custom bash script to polish everything off&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I automatically publish the site to Vercel through a GitHub push&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/posts/openrazer/openrazer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/openrazer/openrazer/</guid>
      <description>What is OpenRazer? I recently acquired a new Razer mouse (Basilisk V3 X Hyperspeed) and wanted to modify it on Linux as well. That&amp;rsquo;s when I found OpenRazer. It is a community-led effort to support Razer peripherals on Linux. The driver supports hundreds of Razer devices, if not all of them.
How to use it I really love the Linux community 4 things like this. The driver works like a charm.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;OpenRazer 3.10&#34; src=&#34;openrazer.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-openrazer&#34;&gt;What is OpenRazer?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently acquired a new Razer mouse (Basilisk V3 X Hyperspeed) and wanted to modify it on Linux as well. That&amp;rsquo;s when I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://openrazer.github.io/&#34;&gt;OpenRazer&lt;/a&gt;. It is a community-led effort to support Razer peripherals on Linux. The driver supports hundreds of Razer devices, if not all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-use-it&#34;&gt;How to use it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really love the Linux community 4 things like this. The driver works like a charm. You can install many different programs that integrate with the OpenRazer driver. I personally use &lt;a href=&#34;https://polychromatic.app/&#34;&gt;Polychromatic&lt;/a&gt; to control the DPI, RGB effects and basically every important setting I need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;secureboot&#34;&gt;SecureBoot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for many 3rd party drivers on Linux, the drivers won&amp;rsquo;t be seen as safe by your systems BIOS per default. Luckily, OpenRazer have a tutorial regarding this here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openrazer/openrazer/wiki/Secure-Boot&#34;&gt;https://github.com/openrazer/openrazer/wiki/Secure-Boot&lt;/a&gt;. Just follow the steps and it should work just fine:)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
