<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenRazer on Elias&#39; blog</title>
    <link>/tags/openrazer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OpenRazer on Elias&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/openrazer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OpenRazer</title>
      <link>/posts/openrazer/openrazer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/openrazer/openrazer/</guid>
      <description>What is OpenRazer? I recently acquired a new Razer mouse (Basilisk V3 X Hyperspeed) and wanted to modify it on Linux as well. That&amp;rsquo;s when I found OpenRazer. It is a community-led effort to support Razer peripherals on Linux. The driver supports hundreds of Razer devices, if not all of them.
How to use it I really love the Linux community 4 things like this. The driver works like a charm.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;OpenRazer 3.10&#34; src=&#34;openrazer.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-openrazer&#34;&gt;What is OpenRazer?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently acquired a new Razer mouse (Basilisk V3 X Hyperspeed) and wanted to modify it on Linux as well. That&amp;rsquo;s when I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://openrazer.github.io/&#34;&gt;OpenRazer&lt;/a&gt;. It is a community-led effort to support Razer peripherals on Linux. The driver supports hundreds of Razer devices, if not all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-use-it&#34;&gt;How to use it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really love the Linux community 4 things like this. The driver works like a charm. You can install many different programs that integrate with the OpenRazer driver. I personally use &lt;a href=&#34;https://polychromatic.app/&#34;&gt;Polychromatic&lt;/a&gt; to control the DPI, RGB effects and basically every important setting I need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;secureboot&#34;&gt;SecureBoot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for many 3rd party drivers on Linux, the drivers won&amp;rsquo;t be seen as safe by your systems BIOS per default. Luckily, OpenRazer have a tutorial regarding this here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openrazer/openrazer/wiki/Secure-Boot&#34;&gt;https://github.com/openrazer/openrazer/wiki/Secure-Boot&lt;/a&gt;. Just follow the steps and it should work just fine:)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
